PRADEEP KUMAR P



@ pradeepkumarnemmara@gmail.co m

9060165095

- A04, Opposite to Mysore lamps. 8th main, Malleshwaram Bengaluru Kar nataka
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/pradee p-kumar-69b95145
- f https://www.facebook.com/pradee pkumarnemmara

SKILLS

Team Leadership

Quality Assurance

Toyota Production System

Microsoft Office

CNC programming

Multitasking

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 30/10/1989

Marital Status: Married

Nationality : Indian

INTERESTS

Listening Music

Story Writing

Travelling

Football

OBJECTIVE

Finding a problem is a half way to solution itself, and Correcting the solution is a development process and this overall experience become the Strength. The strength becomes a product and that become again culture. Want to be a part of curious job environment which rentlessly find solutions and new learning opportunities.

EXPERIENCE

Toyota Kirloskar Motor Pvt Itd

2015 - Till Date

Team Leader-Quality Engineering

- *Established Good Manufacturing Quality Innova Crysta and New Fortuner. (Zero Defect Outflow)
- *Builded strong relationships with customers through positive attitude and attentive response. (Zero Field Complaints)
- *Quality assurance management system implementation in Production process.
- *Worked online with stake holders to improve the product quality.
- *Conducted Asia Pacific Shop Exhibition to market the services.(6 Countries Participation)
- *Product Enhancement activities planning and Execution.
- *Administration and Technical function activities Coordinated simultaneously.
- *Molded team and embraced change to adapt with dynamic market.
- *Exceed the expectations of Customer by giving more built in Quality.

Toyota Kirloskar Motor Pvt ltd

2012 - 2015

Technician

- *Job Role as a production supervisor.(8TMs per team)
- *Setup the line to meet the product requirements.
- *Maximized efficiency with safety.(98%)
- *Trained members with job rotation and Quality Enhancement.(8 nos)
- *Practiced Toyota production system in manufacturing line.(Elimination of Muda Work)
- *Analysed and solved problems using 4M analysis.
- *Work ergonomic study.

Planting Miyawaki Forest.

Watching Documentaries

LANGUAGE

English

Malayalam

Tamil

Kannada

Hindi

Toyota Kirloskar Motor

Diploma Apprentice Trainee

*Worked in automobile production line.(Production

Capacity -180 Cars/Shift)

*Handled Multiple Models Production Pattern.

*Toyota Work Culture.(Standard Work and Toyota Way)

Tyco Electronics

2010 - 2011

2011 - 2012

In plant Trainee

*Product Development Basics.(Moulding)

*Tools for Electrical parts.(Assist tool maker)

*Industrial Practices.

*Customer Types and Services.

EDUCATION

Keltrac 2011

Diploma in Tool and Die Making

Kerala higher secondary school

2007

Plus Two

69%

Kerala Government

2005

SSLC

80%

• PROJECTS

Welding Spot Management

Established Weld spot quality assurance management through Built in as well as Outflow Prevention.(For new models)

ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

Best Safety mind Award.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the information mentioned above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Yours Sincerely,

Pradeep Kumar P

Bengaluru.